Github: https://github.com/dsanderson90

Email: sanderdj90@gmail.com Website: davidsanderson.dev

DAVID SANDERSON / FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Albuquerque-based Fullstack Web Developer with a strong passion for designing, building, and deploying custom websites/web applications. Most familiar with the MERN stack but also proficient in PHP, Laravel, Angular, HTML, CSS and willing to learn new technologies. Resilient and curious problem solver with 4 years of sales experience, excellent interpersonal skills, and the tenacity to solve difficult problems.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Resident Web Developer, ActivateNM (Startup Incubator)

October 2019 - Present

- Provide technical support and consultation to Startups going through the accelerator program.
- Draft and execute project charters. Designed and deployed 2 websites and 1 database.

TECHNOLOGIES USED: React, Gatsby, WordPress, MySQL

Owner, Closure Consulting LLC

October 2019 - Present

 Design, develop, and deliver high-quality, custom websites and web applications to clients throughout New Mexico.

Freelance Web Developer — Self-Employed

December 2018 - October 2019

- Helped local business owners develop or revamp their online presence and messaging.
- Designed and deployed custom websites for various clients, assisted with maintenance, updates, and hosting.

Deep Dive Coding Bootcamp, CNM Ingenuity — Junior Web Developer

October 2018 - December 2018

- Intensive 10-week Bootcamp. 500+ hours training in JavaScript, PHP, Angular, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, GitHub.
- Created a personal portfolio website and worked on a team capstone project (505 Foodtruck Finder) which utilized Angular and Google Maps to track food truck locations.

Realty One of New Mexico — Associate Broker

July 2017 - October 2018

- Guided prospective homebuyers through home buying process. Successfully closed 3+ transactions.
- Conducted Facebook marketing campaigns to target first time homebuyers.

PR Newswire — Inside Sales Representative

August 2014 - August 2017

 Managed account base of 350+ accounts using the Salesforce CRM. Organisations included non-profits, agencies, and small to medium size businesses.

- Consistently met or exceeded 100% of sales goal and cultivated relationships with clients.
 Helped clients hone their messaging and create a result-oriented content strategy that targets their audience.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO — Bachelor's of Science, Evolutionary Anthropology